

# Akshay Gupta

Senior Full Stack Developer

Experienced full stack web developer working in agile development environment to deliver seamless user experience in products. Enthusiastic about development and newly evolving technologies with focus on product details.

+91 88199 45982 akshaygupta.live@gmail.com Ujjain, India in linkedin.com/in/akshayguptaujn github.com/gupta-akshay



GCP

HTML/CSS



### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### **Engineering Manager** PeopleGrove

04/2022 - Present Remote, India

Responsibilities/Tasks

- Mentoring and leading a team of 3 junior developers & close collaboration with product managers and designers.
- Architect & developed a tool to migrate various legacy customer platforms to PeopleGrove V2 platform. So far, 100+ customer sites have been migrated using this tool.
- Leading various tech initiatives like, use react-guery, expand ElasticSearch usage and implement CDC pipeline.
- Worked with Google Cloud Functions (using these functions as distributed APIs or Cron jobs scheduled using Google Cloud Scheduler) & Google Firestore (used for storing active/inactive status of a user on the platform).
- Managed and owned 3 services.

### Senior Software Development Engineer PeopleGrove

04/2021 - 03/2022 Remote, India

Responsibilities/Tasks

- Optimized PostgreSQL queries for 20+ million records. Brought response time of multiple APIs from > 4-5s to < 50ms.</li>
- Architect & developed newsletter service using Google Pub/Sub & SendGrid to send newsletters daily, weekly & monthly. This product is actively used to send more than 500k newsletters monthly.
- Worked on code-splitting in React front-end for better site-load times for better user experience.

### Software Development Engineer II PeopleGrove

04/2020 - 03/2021 Remote, India

Responsibilities/Tasks

- Built Cron jobs for scheduled tasks like sending email notifications and data cleaning.
- Maintained and ported legacy code from Angular.js to React. This increased user engagement on the platform by ~10 times because of better UX (as per our internal Mixpanel funnels).
- Experience working on worker threads for processing CPU intensive tasks.



### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Full Stack Developer (Software Development Engineer I) PeopleGrove

03/2019 - 03/2020 Mumbai, India

Responsibilities/Tasks

- Architect & developed a tool called 'bulk matching' to pair mentees and mentors for mentorship based on their profile data.
   One of the highest revenue generating product in the platform.
- Architect & developed an internal tool called 'launch groups' to make releases behind feature flags easier and scalable. The tool has been used to release more than 20 products so far.
- Worked on Postmark for sending template-based emails.

## Assistant System Engineer

Tata Consultancy Services

11/2017 - 03/2019

11/2011 03/2013

- Responsibilities/Tasks

  Developed an application to feed on the data exposed by SAP OData service. This data was used to create a dashboard, that
- Developed an application that showed various reports generated in Tableau, PowerBI and SAP BO. The application was SSO enabled using Microsoft Azure.
- Conducted more than 10 corporate level trainings for React.js.

helped a sales-person to help decide on whether to go ahead with a deal or not.



#### **EDUCATION**

Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Science & Engineering (7.1/10 CGPA)

Rajiv Gandhi Proudyogiki Vishwavidyalaya 2013 - 2017

Indore, India

Hyderabad, India

Higher Secondary Certification (93.8%)
 Central Board of Secondary Education

2013 Ujjain, India



### **LANGUAGES**

English (CEFR C1)

Hindi

Full Professional Proficiency

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

Gaming



### **INTERESTS**

**Electronic Music Production** 

DJ

Photography